# 摔萝卜炖羊排 好了
Smashed radish and lamb rib stew. Done!
# 羊排冷水下锅 煮它一煮
Put lamb ribs in cold water and blanch it
# 热水一下闷死了
Hot water prevent the impurities from coming out
# 那些浮沫子 那些脏东西
Impurities in the meat comes out
# 慢慢就出来了
slowly
# 我们把沫子打掉了就干净了
Let’s skim it to make it clean
# 搁酒 搁点葱姜
Add some huangjiu rice wine, green onion and ginger
# 我这个比较奇特
This is unique
# 摔萝卜羊排 我把这萝卜给摔了
I smash the radish
# 看您怎么摔
I’ll watch how you do it
# 你看大爷啊
Look at Da Ye
# 酥了么
Is it broken yet?
# 完全酥了您看
Absolutely! Have a look!
# 这纤维全开了
All the fibers are broken
# 比直接切更加入味了 对
Smashing it lets it absorbs more flavours than cutting it
# 你看一磕就掉 劈柴块
Look! It breaks if you split it like this. Split cut.
# （萝卜）飞水 搁块冰糖
Blanch the radish with some rock sugar
# 冰糖 你不管多臭的萝卜
No matter how stinky the radish is
# 只要搁上冰糖
As long as you add rock sugar
# 萝卜（臭）味就没了
The stinkiness of the radish will be removed
# 摔萝卜羊排
Smashed radish and lamb ribs
# 这个季节正好吃羊肉跟萝卜
This is a great season to have lamb and radish
# 就说这羊肉做完的汤我就不要了
Discard the liquid from blanching the lamb
# 换上清鸡汤
Add in chicken broth
# 鸡汤喝着倍儿鲜 肉吃着倍儿香
Chicken broth gives it more flavour, the meat tastes better too
# 好了 捞高压锅里头吧
Ready! Let’s put them in the pressure cooker.
# 小料洗一下
Rinse the spices
# 小茴香 白胡椒粒 花椒 当归
Fennel seed, white peppercorn, sichuan peppercorn, angelica sinensis
# 把这沙子稍微冲一冲就行了
Rins off the sand
# 然后再搁点姜葱
Add some ginger and green onion
# 压上 让它熟的更快 二十五分钟
Cook it with the pressure cooker so it cooks faster, 25 minutes.
# 萝卜出锅
Remove the radish from the pot
# 摔的跟切的感觉不一样
Smashed radish are different from cut ones
# 它特别面乎
It’s softer
# 那边压着东西
While the lamb is cooking
# 我把汤清出来就齐了
I’ll make the broth
# 黄酒 鸡腻子 来点清汤
huangjiu rice wine, ground chicken breast, clear broth
# 一般的来不及吊汤的
If you don’t have enough time to make broth
# 就这种应急的
Use this ‘instant’ chicken broth
# 省去了吊汤的这功夫
It saves the time for making real broth
# 而且效果是一样的 快速鸡汤
It serves the same purpose
# 撒点白胡椒粉 葱姜盐
Sprinkle some white pepper, ginger, green onion, and salt
# 虫草花焯水
Blanch the cordyceps flower
# 羊排一熟 这鸡汤一得就完活
Once the lamb rib is cooked, the broth is made, it’s almost done.
# 水开了 鸡蓉下锅
Water is boiling, add ground chicken mixture
# 攒起来 你看攒个窝儿转
Stir it so it drifts
# 你看 这儿一个漩涡
Looke, there is a whirlpool
# 旋旋旋 东西都旋在一块去了
Let it drift, everything will get together
# 开始慢慢的出沫子了
And slowly
# 渗透出沫子了
There’s foam coming out
# 小魏在渗透沫子的同时呢
Xiao Wei, as the foam forms
# 比如要开锅
If it’s about to boil,
# 要大开的时候你就拧小火
to come to rolling boil, turn the heat down
# 不能大开 一大开就完了
Don’t let come to rolling boil
# 小火 拧小点 火不能大
Low heat
# 似开非开的时候
Let it come to almost boil
# 这样这沫子它就不浑了
So the the foam doesn’t make the broth cloudy
# 这样可以下第二次了
Now, we can add more ground chicken mixture
# 大火再顶一下
Turn the heat up to bring up the temperature
# 让它开着 似开非开
Let it come to almost boil
# 你要不顶它那沫子出不来
If you don’t let it come to almost boil, the impurities don’t come out
# 这沫子不出去这汤清不了
If the impurities are not out, the broth is not cloudy
# 再稍微小一点 还得让它开
Turn the heat a little lower but make sure it’s still almost boiling
# 行了 第三遍
Now, the third time
# 不能有沫子
Can’t let it have impurities
# 大爷讲话 叫清澈见底
In Da Ye’s word: so clear that you can see the bottom
# 关火 你看这汤
Turn the heat off. Look at the broth
# 沉下去了
The chicken sinks
# 经过三遍扫之后
After three times of clearing it
# 汤非常香
It’s very flavourful
# 羊排也好了 出锅吧
Lamb ribs are ready, remove them from the pot.
# 二十五分钟又闷了十分钟
25 minutes and 10 more minutes
# 没味儿 咱调个味儿吧
Not flavourful enough, let’s season it.
# 给点盐 白胡椒粉 黄酒
Add some salt, white pepper, huangjiu rice wine
# 我得把肉捞出来
I need to remove the meat
# 大爷 这萝卜摔完了
Da Ye, the radish is smashed
# 刚才我尝了一块
I tasted one
# 把纤维组织全给摔烂了
All the fibers are broken
# 吃起来绵软了 而且特别嫩
It’s soft and tender
# 好了 把清好的鸡汤
Now, put the cleared broth
# 倒进去了
In the pot
# 鲜啊 再来点
Very flavourful! Add more.
# 开锅就得
Once it boils
# 虫草花 然后枸杞子
Add cordyceps flower and goji berry
# 一道大菜行了
A main course
# 为什么是拆解 把这个菜拆解做
Why do we make the components separately
# 你看肉先压
Cook the meat first
# 压完之后你看 淡淡的香料
So it has a touch of flavour from the spices
# 又吃不出香料味 肉很香
But you don’t really taste the spices, they make the meat more flavourful
# 然后再调味
Then we season it
# 调味之后 清好的鸡汤
And we put it together with the clear broth
# 我们再合在一起
Then we put them together
# 然后喝着汤吃着肉
Have the broth and meat
# 如果肉要不够味
If you think the meat is not seasoned enough
# 我们还可以自己
You can make
# 自行喜欢 调个汁
a sauce for it
# 香菜末 小米辣
Cilantro, "Xiaomila" chili pepper
# 然后我们再搁点豉油
And some soy sauce
# 拿小油一呲 搁点小葱花
Add some hot oil and scallion
# 蘸点汁 别有一番风味
It give a different taste to have it with the sauce
# 摔萝卜炖羊排 好了
Smashed radish and lamb stew is done
# 大爷您看
Look! Da Ye
# 还在咕嘟咕嘟冒着泡儿呢
It’s still boiling
# 汤清味美
Very tasty!
# 看看萝卜
Look at the radish
# 摔的酥烂
So soft and tender
# 是吧大爷
Right? Da Ye
# 这汤鲜吧
It’s very flavourful, isn’t it?
# 这个萝卜摔完了
Smashed radish is
# 效果就跟切的不一样
really different from cut ones